A crash course in revenge.
Death Proof is a action, thriller film directed by Quentin Tarantino.
Austin's hottest DJ, Jungle Julia, sets out into the night to
unwind with her two friends Shanna and Arlene.
Covertly tracking their moves is Stuntman Mike, a scarred rebel leering from
behind the wheel of his muscle car, revving just feet away.
Stuntman Mike, played by Kurt Russell.
Zoë Bell, played by Zoë Bell.
Abernathy, played by Rosario Dawson.
Arlene, played by Vanessa Ferlito.
Jungle Julia, played by Sydney Tamiia Poitier.
Kim, played by Tracie Thoms.
Death Proof is a 2007 American slasher film written,
co-produced, shot and directed by Quentin Tarantino.
It stars Kurt Russell as a stuntman who murders young women
with modified cars he describes as "death-proof".
Rosario Dawson, Vanessa Ferlito, Jordan Ladd, Rose McGowan, Sydney Tamiia Poitier, Tracie
Thoms, Mary Elizabeth Winstead, and Zoë Bell co-star as the women he targets.
The film was originally released theatrically as part of Grindhouse, a double
feature that combined Death Proof with Robert Rodriguez's Planet Terror.
After Grindhouse underperformed at the domestic box office, Death Proof was
released as a standalone feature in other countries and on home media.
It received mostly positive reviews for its stunt sequences and tribute to
exploitation cinema, although its pacing was criticized.
The film explores themes of sports car, sadism,
psychopath, disc jockey, ladykiller.
The tone is intense.